A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 1985-1986
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files 1985-1986
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.882
This collection consists of 20,000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred on 1988 August 25.
Scope and Content Information
These files constitute the major record series generated by the president of the University of Virginia. The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office.
The papers consist of: general files, 1985-1986; seldom used permanent files, 1947-1987; and, affirmative action/equal opportunity officer search files.
Permanent records concern: Attorney General Foundation requests; civil rights compliance reports; Equal Opportunity Programs; and, Lesbian and Gay Student Union.
Organization
Series I: General Files, 1985-1986 Boxes 1-44
Series II: Seldom Used Permanent Files, 1947-1987 Boxes 45-52
Series III: Affirmative action/Equal Opportunity Officer Search Files Boxes 53-57
Series IV: Restricted Files Box 58
Contents List
- Series I: General Files
  - "A" Miscellaneous (4 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - Administrative--General 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - Administrative--Computing Services 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - Admissions--General 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Admissions--Law 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Admissions--Medical 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Afro-American Affairs--General 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Afro-American Affairs--Woodson Institute 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Alumni-Association--General (2 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - American Association of State Colleges and Universities 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - American Association of University Professors 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - American Council on Education (2 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Annual Report (2 folders) 1984-1986 (Box 3)
  - Anthropology 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions (3 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Architecture 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Art--General 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Art--Bayly Museum 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Asian Studies--General 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Associated Western Universities 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Association of American Colleges (3 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 4)
  - Association of American Universities (2 folders) 1985 Jul-Dec (Box 4)
  - Association of American Universities (3 folders) 1986 Jan-Jun (Box 5)
  - Association of American Universities Fall Meeting 1985-1986 (Box 5)
  - Association of Governing Boards 1985-1986 (Box 5)
  - Association of Research Libraries 1985-1986 (Box 5)
  - Association of Virginia Colleges 1985-1986 (Box 5)
  - Astronomy 1985-1986 (Box 5)
  - Athletics--General (2 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 6)
  - Athletics--ACC 1985-1986 (Box 6)
  - Athletics--CFA 1985-1986 (Box 6)
  - Athletics--Finance (empty) 1985-1986 (Box 6)
  - Athletics--NCAA (2 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 6)
  - Atlantic Council of the United States 1985-1986 (Box 6)
  - Attorney General--State (2 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 6)
  - Auditor--Internal (3 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 7)
  - Auditor of Public Accounts 1985-1986 (Box 7)
  - Biology 1985-1986 (Box 8)
  - Business and Finance--General 1985-1986 (Box 8)
  - Business and Finance--Executive Planning Group 1985-1986 (Box 8)
  - Business Operations (empty) 1985-1986 (Box 8)
  - "B" Miscellaneous (6 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 8)
  - "C" Miscellaneous (7 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 9)
  - Career Planning and Placement 1985-1986 (Box 10)
  - Carnegie Foundation (2 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 10)
  - Carnegie Foundation-- College: The Undergraduate Experience in America(2 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 10)
  - Cavalier Daily 1985-1986 (Box 10)
  - Center for Innovative Technology II 1985-1986 (Box 10)
  - Center for Innovative Technology (5 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 11)
  - Charlottesville, City of 1985-1986 (Box 11)
  - Chemistry 1985-1986 (Box 12)
  - China 1985-1986 (Box 12)
  - Civil Rights--General 1985-1986 (Box 12)
  - Classics 1985-1986 (Box 12)
  - Clinch Valley College--General (4 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 12)
  - College of Arts and Sciences 1985-1986 (Box 12)
  - College Board 1985-1986 (Box 12)
  - Commerce--General 1985-1986 (Box 12)
  - Community Colleges (empty) 1985-1986 (Box 13)
  - Comptroller (State) (2 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 13)
  - Congress--General 1985-1986 (Box 13)
  - Consortia--General (empty) 1985-1986 (Box 13)
  - Consortia--Capital 1985-1986 (Box 13)
  - Consortia--Central Virginia (empty) 1985-1986 (Box 13)
  - Consortia--Northern Virginia 1985-1986 (Box 13)
  - Consortia--Tidewater 1985-1986 (Box 13)
  - Consortia--Valley (empty) 1985-1986 (Box 13)
  - Consortia--Western 1985-1986 (Box 13)
  - Continuing Education 1985-1986 (Box 13)
  - Council of Presidents 1985-1986 (Box 13)
  - Council of Southern Universities (empty) 1985-1986 (Box 13)
  - Council of Library Resources 1985-1986 (Box 13)
  - Council on Postsecondary Accreditation (4 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 14)
  - Council on Postsecondary Accreditation--Educational Quality and Accreditation 1985-1986 (Box 14)
  - Council on Postsecondary Accreditation 1986 Apr (Box 14)
  - Council on Postsecondary Accreditation 1985 Oct (Box 15)
  - "D" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 15)
  - Darden School 1985-1986 (Box 15)
  - Darden School Sponsors 1985-1986 (Box 15)
  - Dean's Meetings 1985-1986 (Box 15)
  - Development--General (2 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 16)
  - Drama 1985-1986 (Box 16)
  - "E" Miscellaneous (5 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 16)
  - Economics 1985-1986 (Box 17)
  - Education (3 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 17)
  - Educational Testing Service (3 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 17)
  - Educational Testing Service-"News from ETS" 1985-1986 (Box 17)
  - Educational Testing Service "Examiner" 1985-1986 (Box 18)
  - Energy Policies Studies Center (empty) 1985-1986 (Box 18)
  - Engineering and Applied Sciences (2 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 18)
  - Engineering and Buildings (State) 1985-1986 (Box 18)
  - English 1985-1986 (Box 18)
  - Enrollment--General 1985-1986 (Box 18)
  - Environmental Sciences 1985-1986 (Box 18)
  - Equal Opportunity Office 1985-1986 (Box 18)
  - "F" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 18)
  - Faculty--General 1985-1986 (Box 19)
  - Faculty Letters 1986 Apr (Box 19)
  - Faculty Letter and Responses 1986 Mar (Box 19)
  - Faculty--Third Letter and Responses 1986 (Box 19)
  - Faculty--Second Letter and Responses 1985-1986 (Box 19)
  - Faculty--Initial Letter and Responses 1985-1986 (Box 19)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences 1985-1986 (Box 19)
  - Financial Aid to Students 1985-1986 (Box 19)
  - Food Services 1985-1986 (Box 19)
  - French 1985-1986 (Box 19)
  - "G" Miscellaneous (1-2 of 3) 1985-1986 (Box 19)
  - "G" Miscellaneous (3 of 3) 1985-1986 (Box 20)
  - General Assembly II 1985-1986 (Box 20)
  - General Assembly (3 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 20)
  - General Assembly--House Appropriations (empty) 1985-1986 (Box 20)
  - General Assembly--Legislative Summaries (empty) 1985-1986 (Box 20)
  - General Services 1985-1986 (Box 20)
  - German 1985-1986 (Box 20)
  - Gifts and Grants "A-G" 1985-1986 (Box 20)
  - Gifts and Grants "H-P" 1985-1986 (Box 21)
  - Gifts and Grants "Q-Z" 1985-1986 (Box 21)
  - Government and Foreign Affairs 1985-1986 (Box 21)
  - Governmental Relations--General (2 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 21)
  - Governor's Office--General 1985-1986 (Box 21)
  - Governor's Office--Administration 1985-1986 (Box 21)
  - Governor's Office--Commerce and Resources 1985-1986 (Box 21)
  - Governor's Office--Education 1985-1986 (Box 21)
  - Governor's Office--Finance 1985-1986 (Box 21)
  - Governor's Office--Human Resources 1985-1986 (Box 21)
  - Governor's Office--Public Safety (Empty) 1985-1986 (Box 21)
  - Governor's Office--Task Force on Sciences and Technology (empty) 1985-1986 (Box 21)
  - Governor's Office--Transportation and Public Safety 1986-1986 (Box 21)
  - Governor's Office--Washington Liaison 1985-1986 (Box 21)
  - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences 1985-1986 (Box 21)
  - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences--Career Opportunities Institute 1985-1986 (Box 21)
  - "H" Miscellaneous (5 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 22)
  - Higher Education of 1965 (empty) 1985-1986 (Box 22)
  - Higher Education--Title I (empty) 1985-1986 (Box 22)
  - Higher Education--Title III (empty) 1985-1986 (Box 22)
  - Higher Education--Title IV (empty) 1985-1986 (Box 22)
  - Higher Education--Title IX (empty) 1985-1986 (Box 22)
  - History 1985-1986 (Box 22)
  - Honor System--Monique R. Fawcett 1984-1985 (Box 22)
  - Honor System--General 1985-1986 (Box 22)
  - Housing 1985-1986 (Box 23)
  - "I" Miscellaneous (3 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 23)
  - Information Technology (State) 1985-1986 (Box 23)
  - Institute of Government 1985-1986 (Box 23)
  - Institutional Planning and Studies 1985-1986 (Box 23)
  - Intergovernmental Affairs (empty) 1985-1986 (Box 24)
  - International Students 1985-1986 (Box 24)
  - "J" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 24)
  - Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation--General 1985-1986 (Box 24)
  - Johnson Foundation--Wingspread Journal 1985-1986 (Box 24)
  - Johnson Foundation (1-2 of 4) 1985-1986 (Box 24)
  - Johnson Foundation (3-4 of 4) 1985-1986 (Box 25)
  - Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission (JLARC) 1985-1986 (Box 25)
  - "K" Miscellaneous (3 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 25)
  - "L" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 25)
  - Law School--General (3 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 26)
  - Law School--Promotions 1985-1986 (Box 26)
  - Legal Adviser's Office--General 1985-1986 (Box 26)
  - Library--General 1985-1986 (Box 26)
  - "Mc" Miscellaneous 1985-1986 (Box 26)
  - "M" Miscellaneous (1-2 of 4) 1985-1986 (Box 26)
  - "M" Miscellaneous (3-4 of 4) 1985-1986 (Box 27)
  - Menzies Memorial Trust 1985-1986 (Box 27)
  - Marine Science 1985-1986 (Box 27)
  - Mariners Museum (1-4 of 5) 1985-1986 (Box 27)
  - Mariners Museum (5 of 5) 19841985-1986 (Box 28)
  - Material Management 1985-1986 (Box 28)
  - Mathematics 1985-1986 (Box 28)
  - Medical Center--General 1985-1986 (Box 28)
  - Medical Center--Personnel 1985-1986 (Box 28)
  - Medical Center--Hospital--General (2 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 28)
  - Medical Center--Hospital--Personnel 1985-1986 (Box 28)
  - Medical Center--Medical School--General (1-3 of 5) 1985-1986 (Box 28)
  - Medical Center--Medical School--General (4-5 of 5) 1985-1986 (Box 29)
  - Medical Center--Medical School--Personnel 1985-1986 (Box 29)
  - Medical Center--Nursing--General 1985-1986 (Box 29)
  - Medical Center--Nursing--Personnel 1985-1986 (Box 29)
  - Music 1985-1986 (Box 29)
  - Miller Center (1-2 of 3) 1985-1986 (Box 29)
  - Miller Center (3 of 3) 1985-1986 (Box 30)
  - "N" Miscellaneous (4 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 30)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges (NASULGC) 1985-1986 (Box 30)
  - --General (1 of 2)
  - NASULGC--General (2 of 2) 1985-1986 (Box 31)
  - NASULGC--International Letters 1985-1986 (Box 31)
  - National Science Foundation 1985-1986 (Box 31)
  - Newcomb Hall (empty) 1985-1986 (Box 31)
  - "O" Miscellaneous 1985-1986 (Box 31)
  - Oak Ridge Associated Universities 1985-1986 (Box 31)
  - Omicron Delta Kappa 1985-1986 (Box 31)
  - O'Neil, Robert M.--General (2 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 31)
  - O'Neil--Class 1985-1986 (Box 31)
  - Online Computer Library Center (2 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 32)
  - "P" Miscellaneous (3 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 32)
  - Parking and Transportation 1985-1986 (Box 32)
  - Personnel--General (1 of 2) 1985-1986 (Box 32)
  - Personnel--General (2 of 2) 1985-1986 (Box 33)
  - Personnel and Training (State) 1985-1986 (Box 33)
  - Philosophy 1985-1986 (Box 33)
  - Physical Planning (empty) 1985-1986 (Box 33)
  - Physical Plant 1985-1986 (Box 33)
  - Physics 1985-1986 (Box 33)
  - Planning and Miscellaneous 1985-1986 (Box 33)
  - Planning--Project Status Rep. 1985-1986 (Box 33)
  - Planning and Budget--Capital Outlay (2 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 33)
  - Planning and Budget--Medical (empty) 1985-1986 (Box 33)
  - Planning and Budget--State 1985-19861988 (Box 33)
  - Planning and Budget--University (2 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 34)
  - Poytner Institute 1985-1986 (Box 34)
  - Promotions 1985-1986 (Box 34)
  - Provost (3 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 34)
  - Provost, Associate, for Research 1985-1986 (Box 35)
  - Psychology 1985-1986 (Box 35)
  - Purchases and Supply (empty) 1985-1986 (Box 35)
  - "Q" Miscellaneous 1985-1986 (Box 35)
  - "R" Miscellaneous (5 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 35)
  - Real Estate, Risk Management, and Safety 1985-1986 (Box 35)
  - Recommendations A-Z (3 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 35)
  - Registrar 1985-1986 (Box 36)
  - Religious Studies 1985-1986 (Box 36)
  - ROTC--General 1985-1986 (Box 36)
  - ROTC--Air Force 1985-1986 (Box 36)
  - ROTC--Army 1985-1986 (Box 36)
  - ROTC--Navy 1985-1986 (Box 36)
  - "S" Miscellaneous (1-5 of 6) 1985-1986 (Box 36)
  - "S" Miscellaneous (6 of 6) 1985-1986 (Box 37)
  - Shelton, Jennings R. (Mrs.) 1983 Sep (Box 37)
  - Senate-University 1984-1986 (Box 37)
  - Slavic Languages and Literature 1985-1986 (Box 37)
  - Sociology 1985-1986 (Box 37)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools 1985-1986 (Box 37)
  - Southern Association of Land-Grant Colleges and State Universities 1985-1986 (Box 37)
  - Space and Energy Management (empty) 1985-1986 (Box 37)
  - Spanish, Italian, Portuguese 1985-1986 (Box 37)
  - Sponsored Programs--General 1985-1986 (Box 37)
  - State Council of Higher Education (1 of 5) 1985 Jul-1986 Jun (Box 37)
  - State Council of Higher Education (2-5 of 5) 1985 Jul-1986 Jun (Box 38)
  - State Council of Higher Education Council Notes 1985-1986 (Box 38)
  - State Council of Higher Education--"On Line" 1985-1986 (Box 38)
  - State Department of Education 1985-1986 (Box 38)
  - State Fire Marshal 1985-1986 (Box 38)
  - Student Affairs (1-2 of 3) 1985-1986 (Box 38)
  - Student Affairs (3 of 3) 1985-1986 (Box 39)
  - Student Council--General 1985-1986 (Box 39)
  - Student Council--Minutes 1985-1986 (Box 39)
  - Summer Session 1985-1986 (Box 39)
  - "T" Miscellaneous (3 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 39)
  - Tayloe Murphy Institute 1985-1986 (Box 39)
  - Travel Invoices (2 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 40)
  - Treasurer 1985-1986 (Box 40)
  - "U" Miscellaneous (3 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 40)
  - United States Savings Bonds 1985-1986 (Box 40)
  - United Way 1985-1986 (Box 40)
  - Universities Research Association 1985-1986 (Box 40)
  - University Guides 1985-1986 (Box 40)
  - University Journal 1985-1986 (Box 40)
  - University Police 1985-1986 (Box 40)
  - University Press of Virginia 1985-1986 (Box 41)
  - University Relations 1985-1986 (Box 41)
  - University Relations--News Releases II (4 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 41)
  - University Relations--News Releases (2 folders) 1985-1986 (Box 42)
  - University Relations--Medical Center News Releases 1985-1986 (Box 42)
  - University Union 1985-1986 (Box 42)
  - "V" Miscellaneous (1-3 of 5) 1985-1986 (Box 42)
  - "V" Miscellaneous (4-5 of 5) 1985-1986 (Box 43)
  - Virginia Academy of Science 1985-1986 (Box 43)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review 1985-1986 (Box 43)
  - Virginia Student Aid Foundation 1985-1986 (Box 43)
  - "W" Miscellaneous (1-3 of 4) 1985-1986 (Box 43)
  - "W" Miscellaneous (4 of 4) 1985-1986 (Box 44)
  - "X-Y-Z" Miscellaneous 1985-1986 (Box 44)
- Series II: Seldom Used Permanent Files
  - Armour (2 folders) 1970-1982 (Box 45)
  - A.B.C. Board 1974-1981 (Box 45)
  - Alumni-Assorted Facts (2 folders) 1974-1985 (Box 45)
  - Alumni Association--25th Reunion 1976-1979 (Box 45)
  - Annexation Maps 1980-1981 (Box 45)
  - Architectural and Engineering Services--Selec/Classific. of 1980-1981 (Box 45)
  - Art and Architectural Review Council 1975-1982 (Box 45)
  - Athletics--Polynice 1986 (Box 46)
  - Attorney General--Foundation Requests (2 folders) 1970-1983 (Box 46)
  - Brazil 1983-1986 (Box 46)
  - Charlottesville/Albemarle Foundation for the Encourage. of the Arts 1984-1986 (Box 46)
  - Civil Rights Compliance Reports (2 folders) 1963-1983 (Box 46)
  - Clinch Valley College Building Program 1970-1982 (Box 46)
  - Constitutional Bicentennial (2 folders) 1984-1987 (Box 47)
  - Cotrell Electronics 1972-1982 (Box 47)
  - Dabney, Virginius II 1980-1986 (Box 47)
  - Darden, C.W., Jr. (1 of 2) 1985-1986 (Box 47)
  - Constitutional Bicentennial 1984-1986 Jan (Box Folder A (in facsimile tray))
  - Darden, C.W., Jr. (2 of 2) 1947-1981 (Box 48)
  - Education--(Barnett) 1984-1986 (Box 48)
  - Frank L. Hereford, Jr.-- The Energy Policy Studies Center(1-4) 1980-1981 (Box 48)
  - Equal Opportunities Programs 1977-1981 (Box 48)
  - Flag Statutes 1954-1971 (Box 48)
  - Jeffersonian Restoration Board (1-2 of 3) 1983-1986 (Box 48)
  - Jeffersonian Restoration Board (3 of 3) 1983-1986 (Box 49)
  - Lawn Society-1985 Oct Meeting 1985 Oct (Box 49)
  - Lesbian and Gay Student Union 1977-1985 (Box 49)
  - Malone, Dumas 1982-1987 (Box 49)
  - Research Policy Council II (2 folders) 1980 Jan-1981 Dec (Box 49)
  - Sears Building 1981-1985 (Box 50)
  - Urban Land Institute 1985-1986 (Box 50)
  - Visitors--General (4 folders) 1985 Jul-1986 Jun (Box 50)
  - Visitors--Ad Hoc Committee--Relations/Alumni Organization 1977-1978 (Box 51)
  - Visitors--Special Committee--Board/Student Communication 1976-1978 (Box 51)
  - Visitors--Council of Visitors (2 folders) 1976-1985 (Box 51)
  - Visitors--Special Committee--Investment Banker Selection 1983 (Box 51)
  - Visitors--Special Committee--Search for President 1984-1985 (Box 51)
  - Visitors--Special Committee--University Chancellor Search 1980-1981 (Box 51)
  - Visitors--Cleveland, Angela L. (Student) 1986-1987 (Box 51)
  - Ad Hoc Committee--Reappointment of Dean of School of Commerce 1986 (Box 51)
  - Ad Hoc Committee--Rotunda Furnishings 1976-1982 (Box 51)
  - Ad Hoc Committee--Search for Dean of School of Medicine (1 of 2) 1985-1986 (Box 51)
  - Ad Hoc Committee--Search for Dean of School of Medicine (2 of 2) 1985-1986 (Box 52)
  - Ad Hoc Committee--Search for Vice President and Provost (2 folders) 1985 Oct-1986 (Box 52)
- Series III: Affirmative Action/Equal Opportunity Officer Search Files
  - Restricted Material 1977-1987 (Box Boxes 53-57)
- Series IV: Restricted Files
  - 1984-1986 (Box 58)